♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we've got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we'll withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko stronger after all ♪
Aah!
Say, Odd, why do you always
have to wait for the last second?
Because it’s more fun, that’s why!
Aah!
Is that what you call fun?
Looks more like
insanity if you ask me.
Oh, really?
You mean there’s a difference?
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Thanks, Yumi!
Don’t mention it.
Hiya-a-a--ah!
Odd and Aelita,
you’re only a few minutes
from the activated tower.
Bummer.
I was just starting to enjoy myself.
Careful! Behind you!
Wh--aah!
Well, at last, some action!
Sorry, Aelita!
We’re gonna have to jump!
(SIGHS)
Hurry. I’ll cover you.
Laser arrow!
(SCREECHING)
Hiyah!
Good job, Yumi!
(SERENE MUSIC)
(CELESTIAL HUMMING)
All done, Jeremie.
The tower’s been deactivated.
Okay.
I’ll start the return
and get you all home.
Really? Why?
XANA didn’t even have time
to launch an attack on earth.
You can’t be too careful.
Uh, may I remind you that
going back in time
makes XANA stronger?
I know what I’m doing, alright?
Well, if you know,
then explain it to us!
Just trust me, okay?
Jeremie.
That’s not the point.
That’s my final answer.
Return to the past now.
(WHIRRING DOWN)
Jeremie’s really becoming a pain.
He just flies off the handle
for no reason at all.
He’s like a time bomb.
Who knows.
Maybe he’s got family problems.
Or else, he’s only just realized
he has a split personality
and that when the moon is full
he becomes the
son of Doctor Shrank!
Capable of grafting animal
body parts onto human beings!
And he now knows
that he must face up
to a fate worse than death.
You’ve been watching
Horror at the Hospital again, huh?
How can anyone pass up
such a fantastic program?
Oh, there he is.
How’s life, Einstein?
Where were you?
In my room. Why?
Is there a law against it?
Chill, will you?
We were worried, that’s all.
I’m a big boy now,
so just get off my back.
Hey, you might just
have something there
with your Doctor Shrank theory.
Ah, you see? I told you so.
Right. In the meantime,
I’ve also got to face
a fate worse than death.
What’s that?
Misses Meyer’s class.
Thales' property allows us
to calculate length.
For example, in a
triangle marked A, B, C
with straight lines called
RS and BC, which are parallel.
First, we calculate X.
Then, SC.
Hypothetically, ABC is a triangle.
R is a point on AB.
N is a point on AC.
(SILENCE)
(FOOTSTEPS ECHO)
…equals seven times eight.
10𝔁 equals 56.
And that’s it.
It’s rather simple in the end.
Mam.
Uh, yes, Jeremie?
Question?
May I go to the infirmary?
Oh. Yes, of course.
Do you want me
to come with you?
No.
(STING)
Jeremie skipped history class?
And gym class, too.
And now he’s skipping lunch.
Gym class and lunch
I can understand,
But skipping history class
is not Jeremie’s style at all.
I’m gonna check his room.
Yes?
It’s me.
I brought your notes from the
classes that you missed this morning.
Put them down on the bed.
Jeremie, if there’s anything wrong,
you know you can
talk to me about it, right?
What’s up with you guys?
There’s nothing wrong with me.
I’m just working, that’s all.
I’ve almost found the antivirus
which will free you from XANA.
Isn’t that worth
spending some time on?
Yes, of course, but…
You’ve been acting strange recently.
You should take a break
from time to time.
Oh, yeah.
Does XANA take breaks?
No.
So, what do you want?
You want him to
steal your memory?
I really don’t want
to lose you, Jeremie.
And I can hardly
recognize you anymore.
Aelita.
there’s something
I have to tell you.
(BEEPING)
Huh?
You see!
I told you XANA
never takes a break.
You sure you’re done now?
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
SOS XANA.
Okay, Jeremie.
We’re on the way.
Hurry up.
XANA has launched an attack.
We have to go to the factory.
You over there!
Sit back down!
I said sit down!
(GRUNTS)
I shouldn’t have said
her mashed potatoes
looked like barf, I guess.
If you ask me, this looks
more like a XANAfication.
Cover me.
I’ll try to reach Aelita
and Jeremie at the factory.
No problemo.
Ulrich, on three.
One, two…
three!
Hey!
Ready for another round?
It’s not every day
we get the opportunity
to break up the place!
The activated tower
is in the mountain sector.
Well, we’ll just have to
wait for the others.
What on earth
are they doing?
They’re doing what they can.
XANA has possessed Rosa.
We’ll have to make do
without them.
Hurry up.
I’ll start the virtualization process.
Transfer Yumi.
Transfer Aelita.
Scanner Yumi.
Scanner Aelita.
Virtualization.
The activated tower should be
straight ahead of you.
We can see it, Jeremie.
But there’s also an army
of monsters blocking our way.
I have a funny feeling
we should take cover.
Come on.
Yumi, Aelita, are you okay?
We’d be a lot better if you
could materialize the overwing.
Okay. Coming up.
Jeremie,
How’s it going on your end?
'Cause over here,
we’re starting to run out of ammo.
Jeremie, you’d better hustle.
May I remind you that Rosa’s
specialty is chopped sirloin?
Come on, ladies!
Get a move on!
Odd and Ulrich are
in a really bad way.
No kidding.
All we need here are
some sandwiches
for a nice picnic.
We’ll never get through.
Hold on a second.
I’ve got a little idea.
Little or big, it doesn’t matter
as long as it works.
(GRUNTING)
Here she comes.
Now I know what Tweety
feels like against Sylvester.
Jeremie, what are
you guys waiting for?
Aelita’s in the tower.
Just hang in there
for another 30 seconds.
30 seconds!?
That’s like an eternity!
Jeremie, I think this calls for
a return to the past, don’t you?
Right. I’m launching it. Get ready.
Return to the past now.
What’s he up to?
He should be here already.
Why don’t we go check his room?
Jeremie!
Jeremie, wake up! It’s terrible!
Aelita has fallen in love with Herb!
No reaction.
This is really serious.
Right. I’m calling the hospital.
Look!
His eyelids are moving.
He must be dreaming.
(DEEP DRONE)
(FOOTSTEPS ECHO)
(PANTING)
What could’ve happened to him?
Something must’ve happened
during the last return to the past.
XANA?
I have no idea.
But I think it’s worth
checking out the supercomputer.
I’ll go with you.
Should we search Jeremie’s room?
I really don’t want
to do that, but…
Nothing special.
Except that I just
found out that Jeremie
still wears underwear
with kangaroos on them.
I’ll have to tell him
to move on to boxers.
No activated towers.
But there’s a ton of files.
Hey, I can’t open this one.
It’s called, “My Journal.”
The logs are all normal.
There certainly was a
major discharge of energy
during that last
return to the past, though.
But they’re no different from
any of the previous returns to the past.
Ulrich?
We need you.
Can you meet us
in Jeremie’s room?
Okay.
There. And I…
Got it.
It wasn’t easy, but I got it.
These are video files.
Just open the first one.
Today, I have decided
to start a video journal.
A bit like the diary
that Franz Hopper kept.
This way, if anything
happens to me,
others might be able
to continue my research.
My search to
find the antivirus
which will free
Aelita from XANA
has never been
closer to total success.
And it’s thanks to
Franz Hopper’s diary
and thanks to the data
recovered from sector five
that I was able to
decode part of his diary
that explains how to
use the returns to the past
to logarithmically
increase your intelligence.
I immediately tried it.
It’s amazing.
It’s as if my brain suddenly
had the processing power
of 10 computers linked in series.
A neuronal headset.
Open the most recent entry.
This one’s from yesterday.
Every time I use the headset,
my mental and physical health
gets worse and worse.
But I’m moving so far
forward in my research.
I can’t stop
this close to success.
That’s all we needed.
Is there anything
we can do to save him?
Let’s go to the factory.
I’ll meet you there.
First, I have to
stop by the infirmary.
I want to make sure
that XANA’s attack
isn’t directed at Jeremie.
Come with me.
There are papers we have to sign.
(SINISTER MUSIC)
Hey! My ambulance!
Is Jeremie in there?
Yes, but he isn’t driving it.
(PANTING)
Aelita, XANA has taken
control of Jeremie’s ambulance.
I’m gonna try
to do something,
but I’m really
counting on you guys.
Okay.
We’ll go as fast
as we can, I promise.
Odd, Ulrich,
are you in position?
Ready.
Virtualization in 30 seconds.
I’ll be right there.
The tower is that way.
Sorry, I couldn’t
materialize the vehicles.
We’ll have to go on foot.
Jeremie!
(PANTING)
Jeremie, wake up!
Jeremie!
It’s me, Yumi!
Wake up!
Jeremie! Jeremie…
Yumi, what’s going on?
Just…huge problems.
Same old routine.
Before we can do anything else,
we have to get out of here.
Hey, don’t you think we ought
to stop the ambulance first?
Well, of course I do,
but do you mind telling me how?
Make it fast because we are heading
straight for the river.
Huh?!
There!
(GASPS)
(SCREECHING)
Maybe you shouldn’t have
said it so loud.
I’ve got an idea.
I love it when you say that.
Laser arrow!
(SCREECHING)
(GRUNTS)
Hurry!
Oh, darn it!
Oh, no!
Help had better be
on the way, like, now.
You got any other
brilliant ideas, Ulrich?
Uh…well…
Aah!
Man, that was not cool.
Odd, watch it!
Ulrich! Odd! Aelita,
are you there?
Ulrich!
Yumi, are you okay?
To tell the truth, uh, no.
Now the problem is
how to reach the tower.
Yeah. And fast.
Yumi and Jeremie
have gone for a dip
in an ambulance at
the bottom of the river.
Just a little tarantula
to get rid of first.
Shield!
Odd, leave it to me.
Nice one.
(GASPS)
Aah!
Yumi, we got it.
Aelita has deactivated the tower.
Super. Now we can
drown in peace.
Ulrich, we’re still at
the bottom of the river.
The only thing that
can save us now
is a return to the past.
But I have no idea
how to do that.
Put me on.
Ulrich, I need you to do
exactly what I say, okay?
Yeah. Right. Uh-huh.
Y-Yes--wait, wait!
N-Not so fast!
Where’s the button?
I-I don’t see it.
Quickly!
On the right.
On the upper right
of the keyboard!
The jump button
in Ultimate Blaster!
Uh, okay. I got it.
Return to the past now.
Don’t tell me he’s
out cold again.
Jeremie, no!
I’ve checked the calculations
I’ve done over the past few weeks.
Most of them are wrong.
So, you were
destroying your health
without even improving
your brain power.
I wouldn’t call that a
very good deal.
Do you think that XANA
had something to do with it?
He certainly
put me on the trap,
but the information did come
from Franz Hopper’s diary.
In some way, then, we have
not just one, but two enemies.
Hopper is certainly
not an enemy,
but his discoveries
are out of our league.
I think we’d better be careful.
For now, the important thing is
that you get back to
being your old self again.
That’s for sure.
Seeing you so grouchy,
you were getting to
be like Doctor Shrank,
or even worse.
Huh, Ulrich?
Hey! I am not…
…grouchy.
(LAUGHTER)
Yeah, right!
Gimme a break!
Well, alright.
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY THE FOXTROT FANATICS